In order to further simplify text data,
为了进一步简化文本数据
let's look at some ways to normalize different variations and modifications of words.
我们学习几种方法 将词的不同变化和变形标准化
Stemming is the process of reducing a word to its stem or root form.
词干提取是将词还原成词干或词根的过程
For instance, branching, branched,
例如 branching branched
branches et cetera, can all be reduced to branch.
branches 等 都可以还原成 branch
After all, they conveyed the idea of something
总而言之 它们都表达了
separating into multiple paths or branches.
多个路线或分支的含义
Again, this helps reduce complexity while retaining
这有助于降低复杂度 同时保留
the essence of meaning that is carried by words.
词所含的主要意义
Stemming is meant to be a fast and crude operation carried
词干提取是利用非常简单的搜索和替换样式规则进行的
out by applying very simple search and replace style rules.
快速 初步的运算
For example, the suffixes 'ing' and 'ed' can be dropped off,
例如 后缀 'ing' 和 'ed' 可以丢弃
'ies' can be replaced by 'y' et cetera.
'ies' 可以用 'y' 替换 等等
This may result in stem words that are not complete words,
这样可能会变成不是完整词的词干
but that's okay, as long as all forms of that word are reduced to the same stem.
但是只要这个词的所有形式都还原成同一个词干即可
Thus, capturing the common underlying idea.
因此 它们都含有共同的根本含义
NLTK has a few different stemmers for you to choose from,
NLTK 有几个不同的词干提取器可供选择
including PorterStemmer that we use here,
包括我们这里使用的 PorterStemmer
SnowballStemmer, and other language-specific stemmers.
SnowballStemmer 和专用于其它语言的词干提取器
You simply need to pass in one word at a time.
只需一次传入一个词
Note that here, we have already removed stop words.
请注意 我们已经清除了停止词
Some of the conversions are actually pretty good,
部分转换效果非常好
like started, reduced to start.
例如 started 还原成了 start
Others, like people, losing the 'e' at the end are
其它词 例如 people 末尾的 'e' 被删除
a result of applying very simplistic rules.
是因为规则过于简单
Lemmatization is another technique used to reduce words to a normalized form,
词形还原是将词还原成标准化形式的另一种技术
but in this case,
但在这种情况下
the transformation actually uses a dictionary
转换过程实际上是利用字典
to map different variants of a word back to its root.
将一个词的不同变形映射到它的词根
With this approach, we are able to reduce non-trivial inflections such as is,
通过这种方法 我们能将较大的词形变化
was, were, back to the root 'be'.
如 is was were 还原成词根 be
The default lemmatizer in NLTK uses
NLTK 中的默认词形还原器使用
the Wordnet database to reduce words to the root form. Let's try it out.
Wordnet 数据库将词还原成词根 我们试一下
Just like in stemming,
像词干提取一样
you initialize an instance of WordNetLemmatizer
将 WordNetLemmatizer 的实例初始化
and pass in individual words to its lemmatize method.
并将各个词传入 lemmatize 方法
What happened here?
然后会发生什么？
It seems that only the word ones got reduced to one,
好像只有词 ones 被还原成了 one
all the others are unchanged.
其它词都保持不变
If you read the words carefully,
仔细读各个词
you'll see that ones is the only plural noun here.
你会发现 ones 是这里唯一的复数名词
In fact, that's exactly why it got transformed.
实际上 这就是它被转换的原因
A lemmatizer needs to know or make an assumption
词形还原器需要知道或者假定它将要转换的
about the part of speech for each word it's trying to transform.
每个词的词性
In this case, WordNetLemmatizer defaults to nouns,
在这个例子中 WordNetLemmatizer 默认词性是名词
but we can override that by specifying the PoS parameter.
但是我们可以指定 pos参数 修改这个默认设置
Let's pass in 'v' for verbs.
我们传入 'v' 代表动词
This time, the two verb forms 'boring' and 'started' got converted.
现在 两个动词形式 'boring' 和 'started' 都被转换了
Great. Note that there are other verbs,
很好 注意还有其它动词
but they are already in the root form.
但它们本来就是词根
Also, note how we passed in the output from the previous noun lemmatization step.
还要注意 我们是如何传入 之前的名词词形还原步骤的输出的
This way of chaining procedures is very common. Let's recap.
这种链式程序非常常见 我们小结一下
As we saw in the previous examples,
在前面的示例中 可以看出
stemming sometimes results in stems that are not complete words in English.
词干提取有时会生成不是完整的英语词的词干
Lemmatization is similar to stemming with one difference,
词形还原与词干提取类似 差别在于
the final form is also a meaningful word.
最终形式也是有含义的词
That said, stemming does not need a dictionary like lemmatization does.
这就是说 词形还原需要字典 而词干提取不需要
So depending on the constraints you have,
因此 根据你施加约束的不同
stemming maybe a less memory intensive option for you to consider.
词干提取或许是对内存要求较低的方案